[Music]
foreign
automation tutorial
so as you all know I have already
published around 11 YouTube videos on
tricentistoska latest version 16
covering different topics of test case
automation
so this is our lesson 12 where I'm gonna
teach you about the action modes that
are available in tricentice Tosca 16.
and also I'm gonna teach you setting up
action modes like wait on verify and
select action modes by automating some
of the test cases related to webshop
please do subscribe to the channel click
on Bell icon you'll receive
notifications whenever I publish more
videos
thank you
okay so what is our agent item
so the action modes
are to tell Tosca what to do with test
step value to enter or to steal a
particular control
so basically we are setting up action
modes to tell Tasker what to do with the
test of values that we entered in a test
step
particular control
so if you remember in my previous videos
we already covered creation of test tips
and then
providing the test of values for the
test tips right so
what you have to do with those stepped
up values that we are going to Define in
action modes
and you can select these action modes
within test case section in the column
action mode I'm going to show you
shortly how can we set up these action
modes
and then
there are different action modes like
input
insert
buffer constraint select verify and wait
on these are all the different action
modes that are available in Tasker so
input is a default action mode
that is
provided by the task that means default
transfer values to a test object so in
my previous sessions right
click on a particular control or to
enter the text in edit box we used a
action Mode called input so that's a
default action mode
that transverse values to test object
okay and then there are another uh there
is another
action Mode called insert
so insert is actually used for non-ui
related test cases so I'm not going to
cover this action mode and then buffer
and constraint yes these we are going to
use in try sentence Tasker for the UI
automation but I'm gonna teach you in
the upcoming sessions so for this
session we are going to focus on the
action modes called select verify and
wait on
okay so now let's
deep dive into select verify and wait on
okay what is action mode select so this
is a passive action mode used to
navigate tables and drop down menus
and select table you want to focus on so
basically when you are using an action
Mode called select that is to use that
is to select a table or select a drop
down but not to perform or but not to
send any any values to the control it is
to just select a table or a drop down
menu okay and but if you want to input
or retrieve some data from particular
table then you need to use action Mode
called input but not select
okay you understand right so let's say
if you want to input there is an edit
box or there is a value within the table
if you want to retrieve or if you want
to verify that particular value you need
to input you need to use the action Mode
called input but not the select select
is used to just select the table and
then perform some other operations
within the table or retrieve some values
within the table right but you will be
selecting the table or you'll be
selecting corresponding column and then
you perform some other actions okay so
that's select action mode and verify
action mode this is used to check the
values are the controls right for every
test case we need to have a verification
so first of all verify means what so
when you are automating a test case you
need to have some verification points
right so to this we will be using this
verify to check some values or to check
the controls that are required okay and
wait up so weight on is used to perform
Dynamic weight instead of static weight
so when you use a static weight like 10
seconds 20 seconds 30 seconds it's hard
coded values right so we need to avoid
using hard-coded values you need to use
a static weight that means let's say
I want to wait until these elements are
loaded on the page I want to wait until
this message appears on the screen so
then you need to use weight on okay this
is very important wait on action mode to
improve your test case automation
okay so all these action modes are very
very important
to simplify your test cases while
automating your scripts okay so now
let's jump onto the system and see how
can we use all the Jack all these action
modes by automating some test cases okay
let's jump out of the system
okay
so this is my Tasker 16 latest version
right so as part of this session our
agenda item is first let me cover select
and verify action modes how can we use
these select and verify action modes
while automating your test cases
so if you remember in my previous
four sessions we have completed
completed automating
entire end to end
test case right so let me copy the same
folder here let me copy the same test
case
and then paste it into a parent folder
okay
so once you paste it let's rename this
test case
as
session 12
action modes
okay
okay so right click
so when you click on this shopping cart
shopping costs right click and expand
all I already explained you all these
Concepts okay
so here so earlier when we automated the
entire test case one of the section we
left blank which one so the under
process under process
there is a section called verification
of prices we haven't done that one okay
let me just
mean mine or minimize all those those
so we completed order product we
completed start checkout we also
completed checkout process and then
confirmation page
and verification of success and
verification of prices these two we
haven't done right we have not verified
anything
so in this session
let us verify the prices
of your order if the price of the order
is correct or not and also let us verify
once you click on confirm the order the
confirmation message okay so let's go
back to our
demo webshop let me log in
[Music]
let's go to apparels and choose
order the genes
go to shopping cart
and here agreed to the terms
check out these are all we automated
already and then continue we automated
this as well continue continue
and payment method continue
and then
payment information so here once you
before you confirm the order you need to
verify the price that is getting
displayed for your
order correct so let's take one thing so
let us validate if I select shipping
ground shipping method has ground
then the cost for shipping ground is ten
dollars so I need to verify if
ten dollars is getting
added to my total cost correct so for
shipping ground whether it is displaying
ten dollars or not that's what we are
gonna validate okay for that
verification of price is let's
double click on this vacation of prices
here let me add a module control c i I
already explained you so it's very much
recommended to visit my previous four
videos where I have automated the entire
test case end to end okay so here Ctrl T
that brings up your modules
and I want to add a module called
webshop confirm order
okay so what does this confirm order
contains so let me just rename this as
verify
the
prices
okay I need not to rename this actually
we already named this folder
verification of prices okay
so here
this we have captured all the controls
that are
required for this confirmation order all
these controls we included this table
and everything this button okay if you
see all these prices right this is
actually a inbuilt table
web table this is HTML table okay so
this table can be steered by Tasker if
you see here cart total so this is one
of the table
right so card total is one table this is
this entire price is actually resides
under a table
okay so the same
control has been added the entire table
has been added
okay
and
if you expand this right
column if you see
this is my first column that has all the
titles of the prices
and in the second column
I got the cost of those subcategories
right these are actually two columns
First Column second column okay the
prices are under second call right so
that's why go to column
you have a row and column
and under column you need to
specify this as a hash
two that means I am asking
or I am instructing task card to select
column 2. and click enter so as soon as
you click enter if you see
select as I told you select passive
action mode used to navigate
tables and drop down menus select table
you want to focus on that means I want
to focus on card total table that's why
the action mode is Select here
okay and then I want to select
the column 2. so that I can retrieve
some values or I can verify the values
okay so that's why column 2 has been
selected and then under column 2 I want
to verify shipping
shipping cost so here pick up your
shipping cost here if you see subtotal
shipping payment see subtotal shipping
payment method
tax total right anything you want you
can verify so I want to pick up shipping
okay and if you see if you see the
action mode you need to select as verify
because I want to verify if the shipping
cost is how much 10 dollar or not and
here you need to
specify the value
you need to specify the value
dot 0 0 specify the value of 10 0 0 and
I am instructing Tasker to verify if
shipping cost shipping cost of column 2
has a 10 dollar or not
okay so now see if you I need not to run
this entire I need not to run this
entire test case I can simply
run the section that I want to verify
okay
let me do that okay I want to show you
how you really you can debug by using
scratchbook okay here I already opened
the page of this if I run this only this
step verification of the prices it's
going to verify this shipping cost right
click
run in scratchbook
because I need not to run everything
again it I I'm just running that
particular step to make sure whatever I
automated is correct or not you see here
I got the results if you see this is
successful that means
the shipping cost has been verified
successfully correct if you double click
here you see the expected value is 10
and the actual value of shipping cost
also 10 that means this is success
so
here we covered action mode select and
verify you understand what is the
difference of Select right select is to
steer the
tables but it is not to input the values
it is just to select the table so that I
can
input r i can verify the corresponding
rows or column values okay and let me
also go one more thing
verify verification of success
here also see once I click on confirm
I verified the values cos now I want to
verify successful message right and this
is what I am doing here okay here
verify again that means
I need to select here this message
message order successful message is
visible or not right once I reach here
click on confirm I need to see if this
visible or not okay for that expand what
is the property I want to see the
property of visible property that
control is visible or not and your
operator is equal here true
right and here I need to select action
mode as verify
I want to verify if this message is
visible on screen or not correct so now
again let's run this only step let's run
this step
and see if it is gonna successful so it
is verifying the message yes it got
successful I can see the green Mark here
and if you see here
verification was success
see verification was successful expected
value is true that is visible true and
actual also true that means the message
is on screen
okay so this is how you can
use verify and select action modes okay
it's really really important when you
are actually for any test case right for
any test case when you are automating
you have to verify something
without verification the test case is
not meaningful okay
and what is next agenda next is wait on
so when do we use beta so I already
explained you it's a dynamic weight
basically see when you introduce a
static weight then
it's going to take a lot of time so
basically it's gonna you're gonna waste
the time even though your control or
your text is visible it waits for
the time that you specify when you
specify the static weight but for
dynamic weight
it's really useful if application is
slow it waits for
the control to be visible
if the control is visible immediately it
goes to the next step right so for that
let's go to post condition under post
condition what we are doing
I am clicking on continue here I'm
clicking on continue once the order is
completed and then I'm going to click on
logout right so I'm clicking on logout
let's see here
I am clicking on continue and then I'm
clicking logout but before I close the
browser I want to make sure that the
logout is successful or not for that
what you need to do
once you click on logout you should see
login on top menu right log out see
login should be visible
so I'm I'm gonna instruct taskbar to
wait until the login link is visible
once I click on logout
what I need to do for that let me
introduce let me
control T I want to
insert one more step here top menu step
okay webshop top menu because that login
link available in top menu
okay done and now just drag and drop
step here and rename this as
weight
until
login
appear
okay so what I am doing here as soon as
I click on sorry not here so this step
should be below this as soon as I click
on log out you need to wait until
login link appears log out and then wait
until here so here
login I need to select login
visible
equal to
true
equal to True here I need to specify
weight on
that means
you I'm instructing task or how to wait
until this login link is visible
right
so now let's run this entire test case
and see whatever we automated
till now including price verification
message verification successful message
verification and wait until the
application is log out right everything
so let's close this
let's close this
and right click and run in scratchbook
okay it's going to open the webshop
click on login
apprents and shoe
blue jeans it enters 10
add to cart
agree checkout
building information shipping and
everything
and at the end it's gonna
validate the shipping cost
yes it is validating shipping cost
done it is violating successful
proceeding log out wait until login
close so that means let's see everything
is passed because I can see green color
here
so let's see here
see everything is passed it waited until
login appears right weight was
successful
expected is true this is to then only it
went to
close the browser right
so hope you all understand the concepts
of action modes how helpful
these action modes are while automating
your test cases okay so if you have any
queries
you can provide your comments in the
comment box I'll try to respond to your
queries
thank you
[Music]